







Summary

Jump to Section

8 years of work experience in Information Technology as Desktop & Server Support Engineer, I am Confident of Handling assignments on System Administration and also Soft skills include verbal communication, team building and Multi -tasking abilities

Work Experience

IBM India Private Limited as TECHNICAL SERVICE SPECIALIST Apr 2019 to Till Date

Monitoring and Managing IT environment which has 2,500+ windows Servers

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

- Build, Installation, configuration and administration of Windows 2008 R2 and 2012,2016 servers based on applications hosting.
- Build, Configure and deploy VMs and templates. Converting (P2V) & (V2V) migration of Windows 2003, 2008 to 2008 r2 and 2012,2016.
- Esx Host Patch Upgrade.
- Coordinating with hardware team to fix the issues like drive failure and smart array module failure in HP and
- Coordinating with application teams, Identifies user's needs and matches those to appropriate solutions as well as establishing and maintaining productive relationships
- Providing support for Active directory, Microsoft on cluster.
- Managing and Monitoring the windows Servers using Quest Change Auditor
- windows server patching through SCCM.
- Implementing Group Policies.
- Administrating user's server and share access through Active directory.

Hexaware Technologies as SR.SYSTEM ENGINEER

Oct 2017 to Feb 2019

- Monitoring and Managing IT environment which has 2,000+ windows Servers.
- Build, Installation, configuration and administration of Windows 2008 R2 and 2012,2016 servers based on applications hosting.
- Build, Configure and deploy VMs and templates. Converting (P2V) & (V2V) migration of Windows 2003, 2008 to 2008 r2 and 2012,2016.
- Esx Host Patch Upgrade.
- Coordinating with hardware team to fix the issues like drive failure and smart array module failure in HP and Dell servers
- Coordinating with application teams, Identifies user's needs and matches those to appropriate solutions as well as establishing and maintaining productive relationships
- Providing support for Active directory, Microsoft always on cluster.
- Windows Patching and Software installation using SCCM

Important

· Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld

Transcentra FTS Pvt Ltd as SR.SYSTEM ENGINEER

Oct 2015 to Oct 2017

- * Providing level 2 support for windows and application servers.
- * Involving in Incident, Problem and Change management
- * Server Performance & Health Check
- * Root cause analysis and resolution
- * Server Rebuild & recovery process
- * Working with HP, IBM and DELL Servers
- * Managing network printers.
- * Creating, Managing Users, Groups and OUs.
- * Administrating Software Update Services WSUS for Automated Patch update.
- * Monitoring all the servers' components utilization (Disk, Memory and CPU) using I-enable Rmf tool.
- * Executing ITIL process such as Incident Management via Footprints ticketing tool
- * Managing and maintaining server environment.
- * Configuring & Administering Active Directory & Group policy for Centralized management
- Windows Patching and Software installation using TEM

^ Back to Top

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from ANNA UNIVERSITY, CHENNAI in 2013

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs: mcsa

^ Back to Top

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version	Last Used	Experience
EMC NETWORKER			
Tivoli, Vranger			
VMWARE ESX			
Dell PE			
PROLIANT			
HP ProLiant DL360p Gen 8			

^ Back to Top

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Tamil				

^ Back to Top

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICICIcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQs - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.